[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
Welcome to session 221, TextKit
欢迎来到 221 号讨论会
Best Practices.
“TextKit Best Practices（最佳实践）”
I'm Donna Tom.
我是 Donna Tom
And I'm the TextKit engineer.
一名 TextKit 工程师
And my colleague Emily Van Haren
我的同事 Emily Van Haren
from authoring tools will be
今天也会和我一起介绍
joining me today.
她来自创作工具组
And we're both really excited to
我们非常激动能够
share with you some best
和大家分享
practices for working with
运用 TextKit 的一些最佳实践
So let's get started.
让我们开始吧
First, we're going to review
首先 我们将回顾一下
some key concepts for working
运用 TextKit 的一些关键概念
Then, we'll dive into some
然后 我们会通过一些
examples to illustrate how to
例子来说明如何
apply the key concepts in your
把这些关键概念运用到
app.
你的 App 中
And finally, we'll wrap up with
最后 我们将以一些
some best practices in the areas
在正确性 性能
of correctness, performance, and
以及安全领域的最佳实践结束
So let's start with the key
现在让我们从关键概念开始吧
concepts.
为了确保我们进度相同
same page, we're going to start
我们将从最基础的内容开始
What is TextKit?
什么是 TextKit
And your first instinct might be
你的第一反应可能是
to open a shiny new playground
去在 Xcode 中打开一个
in Xcode and type import
新的 Playground 并且输入
TextKit, except if you've ever
“import TextKit”
actually tried this, you found
除非你已经试过这样做
that it doesn't work.
并且发现没有用
And that's because TextKit is a
这是因为 TextKit
little different than other
与其他你可能已经用过的框架相比
frameworks you might have used.
有些不同
You don't have to import
你不必导入任何东西
anything special to use it.
就可以使用它
The text controls in UIKit and
UIKit 和 AppKit 中的
AppKit are built on top of
文本控件都是建立在
TextKit.
TextKit 上面的
And so if you've ever used a
所以 如果你曾使用过
label, the text field, or a text
label textField 或者 textView
view, you've actually used
你其实已经使用过 TextKit 了
And TextKit pulls together
TextKit 还集成了
powerful underlying technologies
强大的底层技术
such as Core Text, Core Graphics
比如 Core Text Core Graphics
and Foundation to make it simple
和 Foundation 来让你的 App
and seamless for your apps to
能够轻松且完美地显示文本
And every time you use one of
每次你使用这些
these built-in controls, you're
内置控件之一的时候 你都是在
using the power of TextKit to
使用 TextKit 的功能去
show or edit text in a fully,
显示或编辑文本 以一种完全
internationalized, localizable
国际化 可本地化
manner without having to
的方式 并且没有
directly use these underlying
直接运用这些底层
technologies or understand the
技术或者理解
intricacies of complex scripts.
复杂的脚本
And there are a lot of things
还有很多
you get for free too like all of
你还能顺带获得很多额外的东西
these display features that you
比如你在这里看到的
see here.
这些显示特性
And for editing, you'll also get
至于编辑 你也会
access to all the tech services
获得所有 OS 所支持的
that are supported by the OS
技术服务
like accessibility, spell
比如辅助功能
checking and more.
拼写检查等等
And you can take advantage of
你可以充分利用
all of these great features
所有这些出色的功能
without having to write a single
而无需编写
line of code and that's pretty
一行代码 这真的很棒
And so with all of this
有了这么多触手可及的
functionality at your
功能供你选择
fingertips, how do you decide
你怎么决定
which control to use?
使用哪一个控件呢
So let's talk about that,
那我们就来讨论一下
choosing the right control for
如何为你的情况选择
your situation.
合适的控件
And the options are going to be
你可能会有
a little bit different depending
不同的选择 取决于
on whether you're using UIKit or
你是在使用 UIKit 还是 AppKit
So let's review them separately.
所以让我们分别讨论一下
All right.
好的
Let's start with UIKit.
让我们从 UIKit 开始
And first you're going to
首先 你会考虑你是否需要文本输入
And if you don't need text
如果你不需要文本输入
input, then consider whether you
那接下来你考虑你是否
need selection or scrolling.
需要选择或滚动
And if you don't need these,
如果你不需要这些
then you should use UILabel.
那你应该使用 UILabel
UILabels are intended for small
UILabels 适用于
amounts of text like a few words
少量的文本 比如几个字
or a few lines.
或者几行字
And so if you have more text
如果你有比这更多的文本
than that or if you need these
或者你需要
selection or scrolling
选择或者滚动的功能
capabilities then you should use
那你需要使用
a UITextView with editing
禁用编辑的
disabled.
UITextView
Now going back to the top.
现在我们回到顶端
If you do need text input, then
如果你需要文本输入 那么
consider whether you need secure
考虑你是否需要安全的
text entry.
文本输入
And this would be like a
这会像密码栏一样
password field where the text is
其中文本被隐藏起来
obscured and copying is
复制被禁用
And so if you need that, then
如果你需要这样
use UITextField because this is
你就应该使用 UITextField 因为它是
the only control that supports
唯一支持安全文本
secure text entry.
输入的控件
Otherwise, think about how much
否则 想想你
text you expect to be entered.
想输入的文本有多少
And if you want something that's
如果你想要像表单栏输入那样
like a form field input that
只需要一行的
only needs a line, then use
那就使用
UITextField.
UITextField
And UITextField only supports
UITextField 仅支持
one line of text entry.
一行文本输入
Otherwise, if you need more than
如果你需要比这更多的文本
that, you can use UITextView.
你可以使用 UITextView
And so now here's that same
对于 AppKit 来说
decision process for AppKit.
同样需要这样的决策过程
And it's similar to the UIKit
这个过程和 UIKit 的很像
process but there's a few small
但是有些小小的不同
So, again, you're going to start
你也要从考虑是否
by considering whether you need
需要文本输入开始
And AppKit doesn't have a label
AppKit 没有标签控件
So if you need to display text,
所以 如果你需要展示文本
use an NSTextField and you can
那就使用 NSTextField
disable both editing and
你可以禁用编辑和选择
selection to get that label
来获得和标签一样的效果
behavior.
现在回到顶端
If you do need text input, again
如果你需要文本输入
ask if you need secure text
问问自己是否需要
entry.
安全文本输入
And if so, you can use
如果需要 那你可以使用
NSSecureTextField.
NSSecureTextField
Otherwise, we're going to ask
否则 我们会问
our favorite question, how much
我们最喜欢的问题
text do you expect?
你想要多少文本
So NSTextView is optimized for
NSTextView 对展示
performance with large amounts
大量文本进行了优化
And so if you're expecting a lot
所以 如果你有大量文本要处理
of text, you should use
你应该使用 NSTextView
NSTextView otherwise you can use
否则 你可以使用
NSTextField.
NSTextField
Now, unlike its UIKit
与 UIKit 不同
support multiple lines of text,
支持多行文字
but it's still optimized for
但是它更适用于
shorter strings and so you
短一些的字符串
should still use NSTextView if
因此如果你有大量的文本的话
you have a lot of text.
仍然应该使用 NSTextView
Now those of you who have been
好 你们中的和 TextKit 打过几次交道的人
with TextKit might notice that
可能已经注意到
the flow charts are missing an
这个流程图缺少了一个选项
option and that's string
那就是字符串绘制优化
And you use string drawing by
你可以通过在你的
directly calling draw in point
NSString 或者 NSAttributedString 下
or draw in rect methods under
直接调用 draw(at: CGPoint)
NSString or your
或 draw(in: CGRect)
NSAttributedString.
来进行字符串绘制
And many of you may be using
你们中的一些人可能会为了
this for the performance benefit
避免在 Kit 层级上使用过多的
to avoid the overhead of view
视图对象所带来的性能收益
objects at the kit level.
来使用它
And so if you're going to go
因此 如果你想要用这个方法
this route, please keep the
请务必记住下面的几点提示
You want to use it for small
你应该用它来处理
amounts of static text.
少量的静态文本
And you want to limit how
并且你应该限制
frequently you call the draw
调用 draw() 方法的频率
Now if you're calling the string
如果你频繁地调用字符串
drawing methods a lot, you might
绘制方法
actually get better performance
你获得的性能表现可能不如
out of a label or a text field
使用标签或文本栏
because these controls provide
因为这些控件能提供
better caching, especially if
更好的缓存 特别是
you're using auto layout.
使用自动布局的情况下
And if you're drawing an
如果你正在绘制一个
attributed string with a lot of
有很多自定义属性的
custom attributes, this could
属性文本字符串 这也会
also be slowing down your string
减慢你的字符串绘制
drawing because the text system
因为文本系统
needs to validate all of the
需要在渲染之前
attributes before rendering and
验证所有的属性
so for best performance, you
因此 为了最佳性能表现
should strip out extra
你应该在绘制之前
attributes before drawing and
剥离额外的属性
only pass in the ones that are
只保留那些
needed to determine the visual
需要去决定的视觉表现属性
appearance like font or like
比如字体或颜色
And finally, remember that by
最后你要知道
using string drawing, you'll
如果使用字符串绘制
miss out on all of this free
你会失去所有这些
functionality that's offered by
文本控件提供的额外功能
the text controls, so you should
因此只要可能的话
use the text controls whenever
你应该一直使用文本控件
So now you know what you can do
所以现在你知道
with TextKit just by using the
仅仅通过 TextKit 的内置控件
built-in controls.
你可以做些什么了
But if you want to go beyond
但是如果你需要的
what these controls provide,
比这些控件所提供的更多
you'll need to find the right
你需要文本堆栈中
customization point within the
找到正确的定制点
And like much of Cocoa, TextKit
与 Cocoa 很像 TextKit
is based on the model view
是基于 MVC 设计模式的
And the text system can be
文本系统可以
divided into three phases that
被分为三个阶段
correspond it directly to NBC
直接与 MVC 对应
and that's storage, display, and
分别是存储 显示和布局
And so now let's take a closer
我们现在来仔细看看
look at the TextKit objects that
构成了各个阶段
make up each of these phases.
的 TextKit 对象
And we'll start with the storage
我们从存储开始
which corresponds to the model.
它对应的是 Model（模型）
Now NSTextStorage holds your
NSTextStorage 存储着你的
string data and your attributes.
字符串数据和属性
It's a subclass of mutable
它是 NSMutableAttributedString 的
attributed string and so you can
一个子类 因此你可以用
work with it in the same way
你已经熟悉的
that you already know how to
使用 attributedString 的方式
work with attributed strings.
来使用它
And my colleague Emily will show
我的同事 Emily
you some really powerful ways to
将会在稍后
customize the text storage a
展示一些强大的方法
little bit later so stay tuned
来自定义 NSTextStorage
for that.
期待一下吧
Now NSTextContainer models the
NSTextContainer 会为
geometry of the area where your
你的文本将要被展示的几何区域
text will be laid out.
建立模型
And by default, it's a rectangle
默认情况下 它是一个矩形
but you can customize the flow
但你也可以自定义
or the shape of the text layout
文本布局的走向或者形状
as shown here.
就像这里展示的一样
And for more detailed
要了解更多详细的
information on working with the
关于存储对象的信息
storage objects, check out these
看看这些以往优秀的
great past WWDC sessions and
WWDC 讨论会内容和文件
And they'll be available from
这些能在讨论会结束时的
the more information link at the
更多信息链接中找到
And next up is the display phase
接下来是显示阶段
and that corresponds to the
它对应着视图
view.
我们已经讨论了
the display phase quite a bit
一些显示阶段的内容
when we talked about choosing
在我们讨论选择
the right control.
正确控件的时候
And so for additional
因此为获得更多的信息
information, you can again check
你可以再一次查看
out these documentation
这些文件和资源
resources.
这些也可以
from that more information link
在讨论会的结尾的
at the end of the session.
更多信息链接中获得
And finally, we have the layout
最后 我们讨论下布局阶段
phase which corresponds to the
它对应着控件
And NSLayoutManager is the only
NSLayoutManager 是这个阶段中
component in this phase.
唯一的组成部分
And let me tell you it is a
它是一头野兽
And I mean that in a good way
这是个褒义词
because it's so awesome at what
因为它的功能实在是太棒了
So it's the brains of the whole
因此它是整个运作的大脑
It coordinates changes between
它协调所有阶段中的
all of the phases, and it
变化 并且控制着布局过程
itself.
所以这里简要介绍一下
how that layout process works.
布局过程是怎样进行的
So text layout happens after the
文字布局发生在
system fixes attributes in the
系统修复文本存储的属性之后
text storage to remove
来消除不一致
inconsistencies like making sure
比如确定字符串中
that all the characters in the
所有的字符
string are covered by fonts that
都使用支持
support displaying those
显示该字符的字体
And so in this example, the
所以在这个例子中
Times New Roman font is
Times New Roman 被指定到
specified for the entire string,
整个字符串
but this font doesn't support
但是这个字体并不支持
displaying Japanese kanji or
显示日文汉字或者表情符号
And so after attribute fixing,
因此在属性修正后
your text storage will look
你的文本存储
something like this with an
看起来会像这样
appropriate Japanese font
日文字符被
assigned to the Japanese
分配了适当的日文字体
characters and the emoji font
表情符号被
assigned to the emoji character.
分配了的表情符号字体
All right.
好的
So once the attributes are
一旦属性被修正了
fixed, the layout process can
布局过程就开始了
begin.
我们可以认为布局
two steps: glyph generation
分为两步 字形生成和字形布局
And once they're laid out,
一旦它们被布局好了
they're ready for display.
就可以显示了
But wait a minute.
但是 等一下
What's a glyph?
什么是字形
Let's back up and review that.
让我们回顾一下
A glyph is a visual
字形是一种代表一个
representation of one or more
或多个字符的
characters.
视觉符号
And as you can see here, the
正如你在这里看到的那样
mapping between characters and
字符与字形之间的映射
glyphs is not always one-to-one.
并不总是一对一的
So here this string ffi has
字符串 “ffi” 有
three characters, but it could
三个字符 但是它可以
be represented by a single glyph
由连起来的单个
for the ligature.
字形表示
And you can go in the other
其实反过来也可以
Here we have n [inaudible] which
这里有一个 “ñ”
is a single character that can
这是一个单独的字符
be represented by multiple
它可以由多个字形表示
glyphs: one for the n and one
一个 “n”
for the tilde.
一个波浪号
And so going back to our diagram
回到我们的图中
here, we have NSLayoutManager
我们的 NSLayoutManager
performing glyph generation and
执行字形生成和字形布局
And glyph generation is where
在字形生成这一步中
the layout manager takes the
布局管理器（Layout Manager）会
characters and figures out what
获取字符并确定
glyphs need to be drawn.
需要绘制的字形
And glyph layout is where the
在字形布局这一步
layout manager positions those
布局管理器会定位好这些字形
glyphs for display in your view.
以在你的视图中显示
And there's a lot more to learn
从以往 WWDC 讨论会和文档中
about the layout manager from
还可以学到很多
these past WWDC sessions and
关于布局管理器的知识
And you can access them from,
你可以在 没错
information link at the end of
讨论会结尾的更多
the session.
信息链接中
Okay. So now you understand the
好的 现在你了解了
phases of the text system.
文本系统的阶段
And you know the TextKit
并且你知道了 TextKit
components that make up each
构成每个阶段的组件
So now let's explore choosing
所以现在让我们来看看
the right configuration of these
如何为这些组件选择正确的配置
components to create different
来创造不同的效果
So this is your standard
这是你的标准配置
And when you drag and drop a
当你从 “界面构建器（界面构建器）”
text view from Interface
中拖放文本视图时
Builder, you'll automatically
你会自动获取
get one of each component as
每个组件中的一个
shown here.
像这里一样
And most the time this is all
大多数时候
you're going to need.
这对你来说就足够了
If you want a multiple page or a
如果你想要一个多页或一个
multiple column layout, you can
多栏布局 你可以
use pairs of text containers and
使用多对文本容器和
text views, one pair for each
文本视图
page or column.
每页或每列一对
And you can hook all of these up
你可以将所有这些都绑定到
to the same layout manager in
相同的文本存储中的
the same text storage so that
相同的布局管理器上
they share the layout
这样它们就能在
information in the backing
后台存储中 共享
store.
布局信息了
And if you want different
如果你想要让每个视图
layouts in each of you, you can
呈现不同的视图 你也可以做到
do that too, just use multiple
只要使用多个布局管理器
layout managers.
就可以了
And, again, since the text
再次说明 因为文本
shares the same backing store,
共享相同的后台存储
updating that text will update
更新该文本将更新
all of the views.
所有视图
Now we didn't go into too much
我们现在不会讨论过多
detail about these
关于这些配置的细节
configurations because there's a
因为之前已经有一个
great past session that's
讨论会介绍过了
already done that so check out
你可以去看看
WWDC 2010 session Advanced Cocoa
WWDC 2010 讨论会中的 “Advanced Cocoa
Text Tips and Tricks.
Text Tips and Tricks”
And this will be accessible from
你可以在讨论会结尾的
that more information link at
更多信息链接中找到它
All right.
好的
So we've looked at the built-in
我们已经看过了内置
text controls.
文本控件
We've looked at the components
我们已经看过了
in TextKit.
TextKit 的组件
And we've look at how to
我们已经讲过了如何
configure those components to
配置这些组件
achieve different effects.
以实现不同的效果
And there's a lot that you can
在你了解了这些知识以后
do with that knowledge already,
现在你已经可以做很多事情了
but if you need even more,
但是如果你想要更多
you'll need to extend and
你需要自己扩展
customize parts of TextKit
并自定义 TextKit 的某些部分
And so now we'll talk a little
所以现在我们会谈一谈
bit about choosing the right
选择正确的方式
approach for doing that.
来做到这一点
is like building up your text
就像构建文本工具箱一样
It's like going to the store
这就像因为需要一把锤子
because you need a hammer.
所以你去了商店一样
And then when you get there, you
当你到了商店
encounter this giant wall of
你发现有大量的锤子供选择
And you want to pick your hammer
但你想选择
that can do the job and ideally
能够完成这项工作的锤子
the least expensive one that
最理想的是能满足你需求的
will do what you need.
最便宜的锤子
And so these are the hammers
这些是我们可以
that are available to us.
得到的锤子
Delegation is like your standard
委托就是一种
hammer with the claw on the end,
标准的羊角锤可以用来
multiple tasks.
完成各种任务
So the delegates have a lot of
委托们有很多
different customization hooks
不同的自定义钩子
and most of the time they'll get
大多数时候它
the job done for you.
就能帮你完成任务
Notifications is like a
通知就像是球头锤
And this has a ball on the end
它的末端是一个球
instead of a claw so it's more
而不是羊角 所以它更专业化
suited for certain tasks, but
适合某些特定的任务
it's not as versatile as the
但它并不像委托那样
standard hammer of delegation.
是一个全能的锤子
And finally, subclassing is your
最后 子类是你的大锤
The sledgehammer is very
大锤非常强大
powerful, and you can use it for
你可以将它用于
just about anything that you
任何你需要锤子的任务
would need a hammer for but it's
但在很多时候
probably overkill for a lot of
使用它会有些大材小用
And with that, I'd like to
接下来 我想
invite Emily up to show us how
邀请 Emily 向我们展示如何
to use these different kinds of
使用这些不同种类的锤子
Emily.
Emily
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Donna.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Donna
So, as developers, we have a
因此 作为开发人员
collection of controls to choose
我们有一系列控件
from, various configurations,
各种配置
and a wide range of
以及大量的自定义选项供我们选择
customization options to achieve
以实现我们
what we need.
所需的功能
So our tool chest is stocked
所以我们的工具箱
full, but how do we know what
储备充足 那么我们要
tools to choose?
如何选择工具呢
So we're going to take a look at
我们一起来看看
some examples of apps that
一些 App 示例
harness the power of TextKit.
它们套用了 TextKit 的强大功能
And we don't have to look very
这样的 App 示例并不难找
far because almost every app
因为几乎我们使用的每个 App
that we use displays or edits
都需要显示或
text.
编辑文本
We're going to start by looking
我们首先看看
at two apps that we're all
两个我们都熟悉的 App
familiar with and then go
然后一步一步
through the steps of building
构建我们
our own.
自己的 App
So the first app we're going to
我们要看的第一个 App
look at is Apple News on iOS,
是 iOS 上的 “Apple News”
which is a beautiful app that
这是一个漂亮的 App
displays text in a personalized
在个性化以及甄选的
and curated articles.
文章中显示文本
So here's an example of an
下面这个例子
article that is featured in the
是在 “Spotlight” 标签页中
spotlight tab.
“Featured” 栏目中的一篇文章
Now the top of the app shows
现在 App 的顶部显示了
some details about this article.
关于这篇文章的一些细节
Now how could we use TextKit to
我们如何才能用 TextKit
re-create this look and feel?
重现这个外观和风格呢
So let's consider the flow chart
所以让我们考虑一下
that Donna showed us earlier to
早些时候 Donna 向我们展示的流程图
pick the control that's best
以便选择最适合
suited for this example.
本示例的控件
So we have a handful of text
我们有不少文本控件
controls to choose from, but
可供选择
since we want to display small
但由于我们想要
amounts of text, each on a
显示的文本很少
single line, we'll use a label.
所以我们将在每一行都使用标签
Now we can see that there is a
我们可以看到
ton of customization options in
在检查器面板中
the inspector panel.
有很多定制选项
So we're going to go ahead and
我们继续
change the text to spotlight.
将文本更改为 “Spotlight”
We're going to change the font
并把字体
to use the body style.
改为 “Body”
And we're going to enable
我们还要勾选
dynamic type, which allows those
“Dynamic Type” 这可以让
with accessibility settings
启用辅助功能设置的用户
enabled to see text in a font
能以适合它们需要的
size and style that is
字体大小和样式
appropriate for their needs.
来查看文本
Now it's great that we can
现在我们可以在
customize this label in
界面构建器中
Interface Builder, but we can
自定义这个标签 但我们也可以
also see all these properties in
在 Swift 代码中
Swift.
看到所有这些属性
So we can set the text and the
我们可以在运行时
formatting properties
动态设置文本和
dynamically at runtime.
排版属性
Now back in Interface Builder,
现在回到界面构建器
we'll go ahead and add two more
我们将继续添加两个标签
Now everything fits pretty well,
现在一切都很好
but we have one more thing we
但我们还需要做一件事
So looking back at Apple News,
所以回头看 Apple News
we can see that the text on the
我们可以看到右边的文字
right is actually displayed with
实际上显示
two different colors.
以两种不同的颜色
Part of it's black and part of
一部分是黑色的 一部分是白色的
Now we could achieve this with
现在我们可以实现这一点
two separate labels, but if we
用两个单独的标签 但如果我们
wanted to use just one label, we
只想使用一个标签
wouldn't be able to do this in
在界面构建器中
Interface Builder.
是无法实现的
So how could we do this?
那么我们怎么做到这一点呢
Well, we can take advantage of
我们可以利用
the power and flexibility of
NSAttributedString 强大而
attributed strings.
灵活的功能
Now an attributed string is a
attributedString 是
run of characters that can have
一串字符 它可以将属性
attributes applied to ranges of
应用于一定范围内的字符
Now some attributes you get for
你可以轻松地获取一些属性
free like the default font and
比如默认字体
text color, but we can override
和文本颜色一样 但我们可以
these attributes with our own
用我们自己的值重写
values.
这些属性
In this case, we're going to set
在这种情况下 我们将把
part of our string's text color
字符串的部分文本颜色
to white.
设置为白色
Now to see attributed string in
要具体查看属性字符串
action, we'll use the add
我们将使用
attribute method on
在 NSMutableAttributedString 中的
NSMutableAttributedString to set
addAttribute() 方法
the text color to white just for
来讲我们想要的范围内的文本
the range that we want.
设置成白色
And this time we'll set the
这一次 我们将
attributed text property on our
在我们的标签上设置
label.
属性文本属性
At runtime, this looks pretty
在运行时
spiffy.
这看起来很酷
Now UILabels were a great choice
UILabels 对这类文本来说
for this sort of text.
是很棒的选择
Now if we look at the bottom of
如果我们看看屏幕底部
the screen, we'll see a
我们会看到
headline.
一个标题
Now this is also text, but it's
这也是文本
a little bit bigger and it spans
但它有比较大
multiple lines.
占了很多行
Another thing that makes this
使这个文本不同的另一点是
text different is that it's
它是可以
selectable.
被选中的
So which control should we use
那么这次我们应该使用
this time?
哪种控件呢
Now both text field and text
文本栏和文本视图
view support selection but text
都支持选择
field is meant for usually just
但文本栏通常
one line.
仅用于一行
So in this case, since our
因此 在这种情况下 由于我们的
headline can span multiple
标题可以跨越多行
lines, we're going to use a text
因此我们将使用
view.
文本视图
Now when we put a text view onto
当我们将文本视图
our storyboard, we can see that
放到 Storyboard 上时 我们可以看到
we get a lot of lorem ipsum text
我们默认会得到
by default.
大量的测试文本
So we're going to go ahead and
我们继续来
change the text in the inspector
检查器面板中
panel.
更改文本
We're also going to change the
我们还要改变字体
font to look a little bit more
使它看起来更
like Apple News.
像 “Apple News”
And we want to disable the
我们希望禁用
editing feature because the
编辑功能 因为
headline isn't really editable.
标题不应该被编辑
Now UITextView scroll by default
UITextView 默认支持滚动
because they are a subclass of
因为它们是
UIScrollView.
UIScrollView 的子类
But if we want our text view to
但是 如果我们希望我们的文本视图
play well with auto layout, we
在自动布局中良好运行
want to disable scrolling.
我们应该禁用滚动
So this will allow the bounds of
因此 这将允许
our text view to resize to fit
我们的文本视图的边界调整大小
the text.
以适应文本
Last but not least, this white
最后 这个白色背景
background really needs to go,
真的需要删去
so we're going to set it to
所以我们要把它
transparent.
设置为透明
Now Interface Builder made it
界面构建器使得
really easy to customize this
自定这个文本视图非常容易
text view but just like our
但是和之前的标签一样
labels before, we can set all
我们可以在代码中
this in code.
设置所有这些
So here in Swift, we can set the
因此 在 Swift 中我们可以
text and the formatting
在运行时动态设置
properties dynamically at
文本和格式属性
So we looked at Apple News to
我们现在看过了 Apple News
pick the right control, but now
并选择了正确的控件
we're going to look at a
现在我们要看看另一个
different app that we're all
我们都熟悉的 App
familiar with to choose the
并选择正确的配置
right configuration and that's
那就是“文本编辑”
Now TextEdit is an app on macOS
“文本编辑” 是 macOS 上的一个 App
that handles display and editing
用于处理显示和编辑
of rich text content.
富文本内容
Now what most people don't know
但大多数人不知道
is that TextEdit is actually a
“文本编辑” 实际上是
really thin wrapper around
NSTextView 套上了一个壳子
So I want to take a moment to
我想花一点时间
marvel at just how much we get
感叹一下 TextKit 给我们带来了
for free with TextKit.
多少额外的好处
So this is the inspector bar,
所以这是检查器栏
and we get this for free just by
我们通过勾选
checking a checkbox in Interface
界面构建器中的复选框
Builder.
就可以轻松获得
And right below it is a ruler
正下方是一个标尺视图
view which we also get for free
我们也可以轻松获得它
just by enabling it.
只要简单地启用它即可
And everything below that is
而下面的所有内容
just a text view.
其实只是一个文本视图
Actually, it's a text view, text
更准确地说 是一个文本视图
container, layout manager, and
加上文本容器 布局管理器
text storage.
还有文本存储
Now this is the standard
这是 NSTextView 和
configuration for both
UITextView 的
NSTextView and UITextView, but
标准配置
the similarities mostly stop
但相似之处也就这些
So, for example, tables are only
例如 表格
supported in NSTextView.
只在 NSTextView 中受支持
And marveling again at the power
再次感叹一下 我们免费
that we get for free, TextKit
获得的强大功能
provides a table editor that
TextKit 提供了一个表格编辑器
does all the heavy lifting for
为我们完成所有
us.
繁冗的工作
Now when we use TextEdit, we're
当我们使用“文本编辑”时
often editing large amounts of
我们经常编辑大量的文本
Sometimes we paste in a lot of
有时候我们会粘贴很多
lorem ipsum to see that we also
示例文本 来看看我们是否
get a spell-checker for free.
也免费获得了拼写检查器
But really what we want to see
但我们真的想看到的是
is that when we use the format
当我们使用格式菜单
menu to choose wrap to page, we
选择“按页面换行”时
end up with it looking a little
最终看起来会
bit more like a page.
有点像一个页面
We can see that the text
我们可以看到文本容器
container has been resized to
已被调整大小
match the dimensions of a piece
以匹配一张纸的尺寸
Now if we scroll down, we can
现在 如果我们向下滚动
see that the text jumps from the
我们可以看到文本会
first page to the second.
从第一页跳到第二页
Now the standard configuration
标准配置
doesn't really support layout
并不真的支持
like this.
这样的布局
Sure enough, this layout uses
显然 这个布局使用了
two text views and text
两个文本视图和文本容器
Now they're still managed by the
但它们仍然
same layout manager and text
由相同的布局管理器和文本存储管理
storage, which allows the text
这使得文本
to freely jump from one page to
可以从一个页面跳到
the next.
另一个页面
Now if you'd like to see more
现在 如果你想了解更多
about how TextEdit works, you
关于文本编辑是如何工作的信息
can actually find its source in
你其实可以在指南和示例代码库中
the guides and sample codes
找到它的源代码
library.
所以我们选择了正确的控件
controls, we've picked the right
我们选择了正确的配置
configuration, but sometimes we
但有时我们
actually need to hammer on these
实际上需要使用锤子控件
to achieve what we want.
以达到我们想要的效果
But how do we decide which
但是 我们如何决定
hammer to use?
使用哪个锤子呢
So we're going to try and pick
我们将尝试为任务
the right hammer for the job
挑选合适的锤子
when we go through the steps of
在我们接下来一起
building a journal app together.
构建一个日记 App 的过程中
We'll start by putting today's
我们从把今天的日期
date on to the window.
放到窗口上开始
Now we don't have UILabels in
我们在 AppKit 中没有 UILabels
AppKit, but we can make a text
但是我们可以使文本栏
field behave like a label.
像标签一样工作
All we need to do is disable
我们所需要做的就是禁用编辑
Now for the journal entry part
现在 对于窗口的日记内容部分
of the window, we're going to
我们将使用 textView
So in the inspector, we can make
所以在检查器中 我们可以确保
sure that the text view is
文本视图是可编辑和可选的
supports rich text and undo.
并支持富文本和撤销
We're going to add a couple of
我们还要
text fields to the bottom of the
在窗口底部添加几个
window as well so that we can
文本栏 来显示
show how many words have been
写了多少个单词
Now when we run our app, we want
现在 当我们运行我们的 App 时 我们希望
the word count at the bottom to
底部的字数统计随之变化
change, so let's find the right
所以让我们来为这个任务
hammer for this job.
找到合适的锤子
Now we can either conform to a
我们可以选择委托通知或子类
or subclass.
但在这种情况下 我们将
use a small hammer.
使用小锤子
And we're going to listen for a
我们将监听
notification from text storage.
来自文本存储的通知
Now we can get the number of
我们可以从文本存储中
words from the text storage.
获取单词的数量
And when we hear the
当我们收到通知时
notification, we can update the
我们可以更新
string value property of our
文本栏的
text field.
字符串值属性
And when we start typing, we can
当我们开始输入时 我们可以
see the word count change.
看到字数改变
Now if we want to emphasize part
如果我们想强调部分文本
of our text, we can use keyboard
我们可以使用键盘快捷键
shortcuts or the menu to apply
或菜单来应用
formatting like bold.
格式 比如粗体
But it would be great if we
但是如果我们能够支持
could support modern text
现代文本排版工具会更好
formatting like Markdown, which
比如 Markdown
uses control characters to
它使用命令字符
specify formatting.
来指定格式
So if we start inserting
如果我们在一段内容前后
asterisks before and after, we
分别添加两个星号
want it to be bold.
我们希望结果是粗体的
But which hammer should we use
但我们应该使用
for this?
哪种锤子呢
Well, we want to know when a
我们想知道什么时候
change happens, and we want to
发生变化 并且我们想知道
know where a change happens.
变化发生在哪里
But notifications don't really
但通知并没有真正
give us much information about
给我们提供很多关于
this change.
这种改变的信息
So we're going to use a bigger
所以我们将使用更大的锤子
hammer and implement the text
并实现 textStorage() 委托
storage delegate, specifically
具体是 _ didProcessEditing: 方法
Now we can make a new bold font
我们可以从现有的字体中
from our existing one.
创建一个新的粗体字体
And we can add that font
而且 我们可以将该字体
directly to our text storage for
直接添加到我们的 textStorage
the range that we want to be
用于我们想要加粗的范围
And now when we insert that last
现在 当我们插入最后一个星号时
asterisk, we can make it bold.
我们可以将其加粗
Now we're feeling pretty good
我们现在对这个
about this whole Markdown thing
Markdown 功能非常满意
so what if we try inserting a
那么如果我们尝试插入
code snippet?
代码片段呢
Now in Markdown it looks like
在 Markdown 中是这样的
And if we add this last
如果我们添加最后一个反引号
back-tick, we want it to look
我们希望它看起来像一个代码块
It should have a background and
它应该有一个背景和
a header that says Swift Code.
一个表示 Swift Code 的标头
Now this is actually a complex
这实际上是一项复杂的任务
task, so we're going to need two
所以我们需要两把大锤
And the first is a subclass
第一个是 NSTextStorage 子类
Now when we subclass
当我们子类化 NSTextStorage 时
NSTextStorage, we need to
我们需要实现四个必要的方法
And we can do this by operating
我们通过对一个可变字符串的
on a private instance of a
局部实例进行操作来做到这一点
Now let's pay attention to the
我们需要注意
replaceCharacters method.
replaceCharacters() 方法
Now we can add an NSTextBlock to
我们可以将 NSTextBlock 添加
our paragraph style.
到我们的段落样式中
And then we can add that
然后我们将
paragraph style to our text
该段落样式添加到
storage over the range of that
我们文本存储中
code block.
代码块的范围内
Now NSTextBlock by itself
现在 NSTextBlock 本身
doesn't do any custom drawing by
不会自己做任何自定义绘制
So we'll need to subclass that
所以我们也需要对它
too.
进行子类化
Our NSTextBlock subclass needs
我们的 NSTextBlock 子类需要
to have some padding with some
在顶部有一些
extra padding on the top and a
额外的留白
light gray background.
还需要一个浅灰色背景
We'll override drawBackground
我们将重写 drawBackground()
and use string drawing to draw
并使用字符串绘制来绘制
the header Swift Code.
标头 Swift Code
Now this is actually all we need
实际上这些我们想
to do to make a text block look
让文本块看起来
like a code snippet.
像一个代码片段所需要做的
Now back in our custom text
现在回到我们的 customTextStorage
storage, we can create an
我们可以创建
instance of our new code block
新代码块的实例
instead of using a plain text
而不是使用纯文本块
Now, last but not least, we need
最后 我们还要
to tell our text view to use one
告诉我们的 textView 使用
of our custom text storages, so
我们的 customTextStorage
we'll replace the text storage
所以我们要在布局管理器中
on the layout manager.
把原来的文本存储替换掉
Now this is turning into a real
现在这变成了一个真正的
WYSIWYG Markdown editor.
所见即所得的 Markdown 编辑器了
Now a popular feature of most
现在在大多数 Markdown 编辑器上
Markdown editor's is a
都有的一个功能是
side-by-side view with an
并排视图
editing version on the left and
左侧是编辑区域
a rendering on the right.
右侧是渲染版本
Now we can do this with two text
我们可以通过使用
views side-by-side.
两个文本视图来实现
We'll disable editing for the
我们停用右侧视图的编辑功能
And now we have two text views
现在我们有两个文本视图
but we want them to display the
虽然我们希望它们显示
same content but look a little
相同的内容 但我们还希望
different on the right.
右边视图能够看起来不太一样
So we want a configuration like
所以我们需要一个像这样的配置
this where we have one text
两个视图的文本存储器相同
storage but two of everything
而所有其他都不同
To do this, we will replace the
为此 我们
text storage on the right with
将用左侧的文本存储
that from the left.
把右侧的替换掉
Now let's see what this looks
现在让我们看看
like.
这是什么样子
Now this is actually really
现在这真的很酷
cool.
如果我们在左侧添加任何字符
left, they'll show up
它们将立即显示在右侧
Now usually the right-hand side
现在通常右手边
doesn't really show the Markdown
并没有真正显示 Markdown 字符
characters but since this is a
但由于这是一个
shared text storage, it means we
共享文本存储 这意味着我们
have to hide the characters
必须隐藏字符
during the layout process.
在布局过程中
Now since we need to do it this
因为我们需要这样做
way, we really only have one
所以我们实际上只有一个选择
option and that's to implement
那就是实现
the shouldGenerateGlyphs method
NSLayoutManager 委托上的
on the NSLayoutManager delegate.
shouldGenerateGlyphs() 方法
This will allow us to intervene
这将允许我们介入
in the glyph generation process.
字形生成过程
So we can take the glyphs that
因此 我们可以
are about to be laid out and if
获取即将布局的字形
they represent a Markdown
并且如果它们表示 Markdown
control character, we can apply
命令字符 我们可以将
the null property to that glyph.
.null 属性应用于该字形
Now this will eliminate the
现在 这将让字形
glyph altogether during the
在布局过程中被
layout process without changing
彻底消除 而不会更改
the underlying text storage.
底层的文本存储
Then, we will use the new glyphs
然后 我们将使用新的字形
and tell the layout manager that
并告诉布局管理器
we want to present these glyphs
我们想要用这些新的属性
with our new properties.
来呈现这些字形
Now this is actually really
这真的很酷
cool.
所以左侧显示了
editable version with all the
可编辑版本
Markdown characters included.
包含所有 Markdown 字符
And the right-hand side shows no
而右侧没有显示
Markdown characters all, all
任何 Markdown 字符
using the same text storage.
全部使用相同的文本存储
Now building a side-by-side
现在构建一个并排的
Markdown editor is not something
Markdown 编辑器 并不是
all of us do every day, but it
我们每天都在做的事情
was really good to see how
但是很开心看到
customizable TextKit is with
TextKit 的可自定义度是多么高
real world examples.
以及它是如何与现实的例子结合的
If you'd like to learn more
如果你想了解更多
about how to use and customize
关于如何使用和自定义
TextKit, check out our amazing
TextKit 的信息 请查看我们出色的
programming guides.
编程指南
And with that, I will hand it
然后 我要把现场交给 Donna
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Emily.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Emily
Those are some really cool
这些例子真的
examples.
非常酷
And I really hope you'll be able
我真的希望你能够
to take some of the techniques
采用她展示的一些技术
that she showed off and use them
并在你自己的 App 中使用它们
But now let's shift gears a bit
但现在让我们稍微转换一下
and talk about some best
并讨论一些
practices for working with text.
使用文本的最佳做法
So on the topic of correctness,
关于正确性
if your text doesn't render the
如果你的文本没有
way you expect, it could be
按照你期望的方式呈现
related to incomplete or
它可能与属性字符串上的
incorrect attributes on your
不完整或不正确的
attributed string.
属性有关
And so let's take a look at an
所以我们来看看一个例子
example to see this in practice.
在实践中看到这一点
Let's say we have a UITextView
假设我们有一个 UITextView
with some attributed text that
它带有一些属性文本
says don't hate.
写着 “Don't hate.”
And it says this in the font
这段文本的格式是
Comic Sans 24 point.
Comic Sans 字体 24 号大小
And we want to programmatically
我们希望以编程的方式
apply a bold typeface to the
把它设置成粗体
word don't because if there's
因为如果有
any font more universally hated
任何比 Comic Sans 令人讨厌的字体
than Comic Sans, it's Comic Sans
那一定是 Comic Sans Bold
And so at first blush, it might
所以乍一看
seem reasonable to write code
编写这样的代码似乎是合理的
Now here we have our original
现在 我们有我们的原始字体
And we're going to use a font
我们将使用一个 fontDescriptor
descriptor to create a bold
来创建原始字体
version of this original font.
的粗体版本
Then, we're going to initialize
然后 我们要
our mutable attributed string
使用原始文本
using the original text.
初始化可变属性字符串
We're going to apply our new
我们要将我们的
font or new bold font to the
新字体或新的粗体字体应用于
word don't and that's going to
单词 “Don't”
be the first five characters.
这是前五个字符
And then we're going to set the
然后我们将设置
attributed text property of our
我们的 UITextView 的属性文本属性
UITextView to use this new
来使用这个新的
attributed string except when we
属性字符串 但是我们这样做时
do that we'll see that our new
我们会看到
bold font applied to the word
应用于该单词的新的粗体字体
don't just as we expected but
确实像我们预期的那样
the rest of the string somehow
但字符串其余的部分
lost the original font.
不知道为什么丢失了原始字体
And now those of you who despise
现在 那些不喜欢
Comic Sans might be happy about
Comic Sans 的人可能会为此感到高兴
that, but the result is wrong
但结果是错误的
and so that warrants a sad face.
所以这是一个悲伤的故事
So why did this happen?
那么为什么会这样呢
And to answer that, let's take a
为了回答这个问题 让我们
closer look at how we're
仔细看看我们是如何
initializing our attributed
初始化我们的
string.
属性字符串的
So notice that we're using a
所以请注意 我们要使用
plain text string to initialize
纯文本字符串来初始化它
it, and we're using the
并且我们使用的
initializer with no attribute
初始化程序没有属性信息
And when you create a new
当你创建一个新的
attributed string and you don't
属性字符串 并且你没有
provide any attribute
提供任何属性信息时
information, that new attributed
新的属性字符串
string, we use the default
会使用默认的属性
And the default font is
默认字体是
Helvetica 12 point.
Helvetica 12 号
And so to recap what happened,
为了回顾发生了什么
we started with this original
我们开始
attributed string with the font
从这个原始的属性字符串
Comic Sans 24 applied to the
将字体 Comic Sans 24 应用于
entire range.
整个范围
And then we created this new
然后我们创建了这个新的
attributed string, and it got
属性字符串
initialized with the default
并使用默认属性
attributes.
进行了初始化
And we applied our bold font to
并且我们将粗字体应用于
the word don't on this new
新字符串上的 “Don't”
string, and we ended up with
结果就是这里这个
this incorrect result here where
不正确的结果 其中
the word don't is in Comic Sans
“Don't” 以 Comic Sans 粗体 24 号显示
bold 24, and the rest of the
但字符串的其余部分
string is in the default font of
处于默认字体
Helvetica 12.
Helvetica 12
And so there are two different
有两种不同的方法
ways that we could do this
可以让它们正确地显示
correctly and one way is to
一种方法是
avoid mixing the plain and
避免将纯文本
attributed text altogether.
和属性文本混合在一起
So by initializing our new
因此 通过使用原始字符串
attributed string using the
来初始化我们的新属性字符串
original one, we're going to
我们要把
keep those original attributes.
那些原始属性保留下来
And then we can apply our new
然后我们再应用我们的新属性
attributes without getting this
而不会看到这个
reset effect with the default
重设的默认效果
But it's not always feasible to
但是 避免混合纯文本和属性文本
attributed text.
并不总是可行的
So if you've got to mix it up,
因此 如果你必须将其混合
you can explicitly supply the
则可以在从纯文本字符串中
attributes when creating that
创建新的属性字符串时
new attributed string from the
明确提供属性
And if we make sure to apply the
如果我们确保
same attributes from the
从原始文本中应用相同的属性
original text, we'll get the
我们就会得到
correct result.
正确的结果
But you should be aware that
但是你应该知道
this reset effect can happen
重设效果会发生
with any attributes that have
在任何具有默认值
default values and not just
而不仅仅是字体的属性的情况下
And as you can see, there are a
如你所见
lot of attributes with default
有很多属性都具有默认值
values.
所以我想特别提醒一下
paragraph style here in
这里的 “Paragraph style（段落风格）”
particular as being a sneaky
因为它是一个隐蔽的
reset point.
重置点
And to see why, we'll revisit
为了明白为什么
our earlier example.
我们将重新回顾一下前面的例子
But instead of changing the
但不是改变字体
font, we're going to change the
我们将改变段落风格
paragraph style to truncate the
来屏蔽 “hate” 这个词
word hate because nobody likes
因为没有人喜欢仇恨
So we want our text to look like
所以我们希望我们的文本看起来像这样
this, but when we run this code,
但是当我们运行这段代码时
we'll get a result like this
我们将得到
with all of the text in
一个这样的结果
Helvetica 12 and using the
所有文本的格式都是 Helvetica 12
default paragraph style with the
使用默认的段落风格
default line break mode of word
默认的换行模式 和默认的自动断词
And, again, this is really great
又一次 对于那些
for those of you who loathe
讨厌 Comic Sans 的人来说 真是太棒了
Comic Sans because it's been
因为它已经被完全地
totally eliminated from the
从字符串中移除了
string but it's wrong.
但它=这是错误的
And it's wrong in a different
但是这次错误的原因
way from last time.
与上次不同
And to understand the
为了更好地理解这不同
difference, let's recall that
让我们回顾一下
attribute fixing happens before
属性修复发生在
layout and this is where the
布局之前 这时候
system repairs the inconsistent
系统会修复不一致的属性
And so here in our attributed
在我们的属性字符串中
string we have a single
我们有一个
paragraph with multiple
包含多个段落样式的单个段落
paragraph styles and that's
这显然非常不一致
So when the system fixes the
因此 当系统修复
attributes of this string, it's
此字符串的属性时
going to take the first
它将采用
paragraph style it finds and
它找到的第一段样式
apply it to the entire
并将其应用于整个段落
And that's how we ended up with
这就会导致
our attributed string displaying
我们的属性字符串
with the default paragraph
以默认段落样式显示
And the key take away here is to
关键是要明确你的属性
attributes, especially when
特别是在混合纯文本和
attributed text.
属性文本时
So by doing this, you're going
所以通过这样做
to avoid this reset effect with
你就能避免它出现
the default attributes.
默认属性的重置效果
And for AppKit developers, this
对于 AppKit 开发人员来说
is actually super important if
如果你正在为 App 更新
you're updating your app for
深色模式
dark mode.
这一点尤其重要
So by using the explicit
因此通过使用
attributes with the dynamic
带有动态颜色的显式属性
colors like NSColor.textColor,
如 NSColor.textColor
you'll ensure that your text is
可以确保你的文本
drawn with the correct colors
会根据环境用正确的
for the context.
颜色绘制
So moving on.
继续
The next topic is performance.
下一个话题是性能
If you're working with large
如果你使用大量文本
amounts of text, a good way to
一个提高 App 性能的
improve your apps performance is
好方法是
to use noncontinuous layout.
使用非连续布局
And to understand what that
为了明白这意味着什么
means, let's revisit our old
让我们重新回顾
friend the layout process.
布局过程
We said that the layout process
我们说过布局过程
consists of glyph generation
包括字形生成
followed by glyph layout.
和字形布局
And so with continuous layout,
所以对于连续布局
the layout manager is going to
布局管理器
perform glyph generation and
在文本存储开头就开始
glyph layout starting at the
执行字形生成和
beginning of the text storage.
字形布局了
And it goes in order from the
它以从头到尾的顺序进行
And so if someone using your app
所以如果有人使用你的 App
scrolls to some point in the
滚动到文本视图中间的某个点
layout manager has to generate
那么布局管理器
and layout the glyphs for all
必须为红色矩形
the glyphs that come before that
所指示区域之前的所有字形
point as indicated by the red
生成并布局字形
And note that this also includes
并且请注意
the text that you can't see
这还包括你从
that's been scrolled off the top
屏幕顶部滚动回到
of the screen all the way back
文本存储起点之间
to the beginning of the text
所有你看不见的文本
And so if you have a lot of
所以如果你有很多文本
text, that poor person might
那么这个可怜的用户
have to wait a while for your
可能需要等待你的 App 一段时间
app to finish layout but
让它完成布局
luckily, we can avoid this
但幸运的是
situation by using noncontinuous
我们可以通过使用非连续布局
layout.
来避免这种情况
And so as the name implies, with
正如其名称所暗示的那样
noncontinuous layout, the layout
使用非连续布局
manager doesn't have to do glyph
布局管理器无需
generation and layout in order
从文本存储开始
from the beginning of the text
顺序地进行字形
storage.
生成和布局
So now when that person, using
所以现在当这个使用你 App 的人
your app, scrolls to the middle
滚动到文本视图的中间时
of your text view, the layout
布局管理器可以
manager can perform glyph
立即为该中间部分
generation and layout for that
执行字形生成和布局
So if your text storage has a
所以如果你的文本存储中
lot of text in it, using
有很多文本
noncontinuous layout is a huge
使用非连续布局可以
performance win.
为你带来巨大的性能提升
Great. So how do you turn this
那么你如何启用
on?
这个功能呢
Well, noncontinuous layout is a
非连续布局是
property of NSLayoutManager.
NSLayoutManager 的一个属性
And so for NSTextView, you can
对于 NSTextView
access the text to use layout
你可以使用布局管理器
manager and then you can set
来访问文本
that property there.
然后在其中设置该属性
For UITextView, you usually
对于 UITextView
don't have to do anything
你通常不需要做任何事情
because this is turned on by
因为这是默认开启的
default, but there's just one
但只需要记住一件重要的事情
Since UITextView is a subclass
由于 UITextView 是 UIScrollView 的子类
of UIScrollView, noncontinuous
因此非连续布局
layout will require scrolling to
需要启用滚动
be enabled.
才能生效
And this is because when you
这是因为当你禁用滚动时
disable scrolling, asking for
询求你的文本视图
the intrinsic content size of
所包含的内容大小
your text view is going to
需要布局
require laying out all the text
所有的文本
and then you wouldn't get the
所以你根本
performance benefits of
不会获得
noncontinuous layout in the
非连续布局的
first place.
性能优势
And that brings me to a really
这把我们引导了一个
important point.
很重要的问题上
You should avoid requesting
当你使用非连续布局时
layout for all or most of the
你应该避免一次
text at once when you're using
请求全部或者大多数文本的布局
noncontinuous layout since that
因为这样做
kind of defeats the purpose of
从根本上就
using it in the first place.
违背了我们的初衷
So if you have only one text
所以如果你只有一个文本容器
container, don't ask for the
不要要求
layout of the entire thing.
整个容器的布局
And don't ask for layout for
并且不要要求
large ranges of characters or
包含文本结尾的大范围字符
glyphs that include the end of
或字形的布局
And we didn't dig too deeply
我们并没有深入
into the topic of text
研究文本性能的主题
performance here because I gave
因为 我在去年的 WWDC 2017 上针对这一点
at WWDC 2017, Efficient
进行了一次非常棒的演讲
unteractions with Frameworks.
那就是框架效率的不完整性
And you can access the video
你可以在讨论会结束时
from that more information link
通过更多信息链接
at the end of the session.
访问该视频
All right.
好的
Now it's time to talk about
现在是时候谈论
everyone's favorite topic,
每个人最喜欢的话题
security.
安全
So you may have noticed that
你可能已经注意到
there have been incidents in the
最近有一些事件发生在互联网上
recent past where some people on
某些人利用我们软件中的错误
the Internet have exploited bugs
来给使用我们产品的人们制造麻烦
And in response, we're
作为回应
continuing to devise techniques
我们正在继续设计
for mitigating these kinds of
抵御这类攻击的技术
attacks, but today I'd like to
但今天我想谈谈
talk about how we can work
我们如何共同努力
together to provide a stronger
为这些攻击
defense against these attacks.
提供更强大的防御
So you may have heard of the
所以你可能已经听说过
concept defense in depth.
纵深防御的概念
And in case you're not familiar
如果你不熟悉
with the terms, defense in depth
这些术语的话 纵深防御
refers to creating multiple
就是创建多层保护
against threats.
来抵御威胁
And this concept has been around
这个概念已经存在了几个世纪了
You can see it in the design of
你可以在中世纪城堡的设计中
medieval castles.
看到它
The land around the outside is
城堡周围的地上没有树木
clear of trees so you can see
所以你可以看到袭击者来了
And there's a moat to make
还有一个护城河
approaching the castle more
可以让城堡更加难以接近
difficult and to prevent
并且可以防止敌人在
tunneling underneath it.
下面挖隧道
And the walls are another
而墙壁是另一道防线
They're built tall so that
它们很高
they're difficult to climb.
所以很难攀爬
And there are arrow slits in the
并且在墙壁和顶部
walls and crenellations at the
有很多垛口
top to allow defenders to fire
让防御者能在
on attackers from protected
有防御的地方
locations.
向攻击者开火
Now any one of these individual
这些保护中单独
protections might not be enough
任何一种都可能不足以
to fend off an attack but
抵御攻击
collectively they provide a
但它们组合在一起
strong defense.
就提供了强有力的防御
And like the castle, we here at
就像城堡一样
Apple provide multiple layers of
我们在这里为攻击
defense against attacks, but
提供了多层防御
there's nothing stopping you
但没没有人会阻止
from also taking your own
你在你的 App 或框架中
defensive measures in your app
采取自己的
or framework.
防御措施
And by doing this, you're adding
通过这样做
another layer of protection and
你可以添加另一层保护
improving your product security.
并提高产品安全性
Everyone wins.
这是共赢
So let's talk about what you can
那么让我们来谈谈
do here.
你可以在这里做什么
And something I'd like you to
而我希望你考虑的是
consider is setting limits on
在你的 App 或框架中
text input in your app or
设置文本输入限制
And now I'd like to emphasize
现在我想强调
that this might not always make
这可能并不总是
sense to do.
有意义的
So, for example, if your app is
因此举例来说
an authoring tool like that
如果你的 App 是
journal app that Emily showed
Emily 之前展示的那种
earlier, it wouldn't really make
日记 App 的创作工具
any sense to set a limit on the
那么对该文本的长度设置限制
length of the text there.
并没有任何意义
So if it doesn't make sense, you
所以如果没有意义
shouldn't do it.
你就不应该这样做
But in contrast, if your phone
但相比之下
app has a text field for
如果你的手机 App 有一个
assigning a nickname to an
用于为帐户分配昵称的
account, you probably have some
文本域 那么你可能会想
idea what a reasonable limit
在这里应该设定怎样的限制
would be there.
才合理
And it's a good idea to set
设置这些限制是个好主意
these limits because all text
因为所有文本输入
input is potentially untrusted.
都有潜在的风险
When you allow text input, you
当你允许文本输入时
allow copy and paste.
你就允许了复制和粘贴
You don't know what kind of text
你不知道其中会被
can be pasted in there.
粘贴哪种文本
It could be anything.
它可能是任何东西
It could be a string with
它可能是一个
malicious character
带有恶意字符组合的字符串
combinations, or it could just
或者它可能只是
be a string that's really,
一个非常
really, really long.
非常长的字符串
And even though long strings
即使像这样的长字符串
like that may not be malicious
本身可能不是恶意的
in themselves, it could cause
它也可能会导致你的 App
your app to freeze or hang.
冻结或卡住
So if you have a text field
如果你有一个文本域
that's intended for one line of
是为了一行输入设计的
input and someone pastes the
但有人想将“战争与和平”的
entire contents of "War and
全部内容粘贴进去
Peace" into it, which is about
这大约有 310 万个
3.1 million characters in
英文字符
English, is that reasonable?
这是否合理
Probably not.
可能并不
So this is a great example of a
所以这是一个很好的例子
case where it makes sense to
它可以让你能强制增加
impose your own limits.
你自己的限制
And here are the recommended
以下是
approaches for setting these
设定这些限制的推荐方法
You want to validate the input
你希望在输入字符串
string before it's set on the
在文本域上设置之前进行验证
And so for UITextFields, you can
对于 UITextFields
do this by using
你可以通过
UITextFieldDelegate.
使用 UITextFieldDelegate 来完成此操作
And for NSTextFields, you should
对于 NSTextFields
use a custom NSFormatter to
你应该使用自定义的 NSFormatter
implement your validation logic.
来实现你的验证逻辑
Oh, and we've also got some
而且我们还有一些额外的
additional security enhancements
安全增强功能即将推出
So keep an eye out for them in
因此请在发布说明中注意它们
the release notes and come see
如果你有任何问题
us at the labs this week if you
请在本周的实验室中
have any questions.
联系我们
All right.
好的
We're just about out of time so
时间要到了
let's recap.
所以让我们回顾一下
You know how to choose the right
你知道如何选择正确的控件
control, customization point,
自定义点
and customization approach and
和自定义方法
you know the best practices to
并了解在正确性
follow in the areas of
性能和安全性方面
correctness, performance, and
遵循的最佳实践
So use this knowledge to go
使用这些知识和 TextKit
forth and create great things
去创伟大的东西吧
Oh, and before you go, here's
等等
that super important more
这里是超级重要的
information link where you can
更多信息链接
find all of the great past
你可以在这里找到
sessions and documentation that
我们今天引用的
we've referenced today.
所有过去的优秀讨论会和文档
And come visit us at the labs on
请在星期四和星期五来
Thursday and Friday.
我们实验室参观
Thank you and enjoy the rest of
谢谢 希望你们可以享受讨论会的
the conference.
其余部分
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]